Inventory of the World Federalist Association of Northern California records
Hoover Institution Archives
World Federalist Association of Northern California records
1990-1998
2014C44
Hoover Institution Archives
10 manuscript boxes (4 linear feet)
Minutes, correspondence, transcripts of forum proceedings, financial records, and printed matter, relating to international organization and the United Nations, and especially to the 22nd World Congress of the World Federalist Movement, held in San Francisco in 1995.
World Federalist Association of Northern California..
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
Branch of the World Federalist Association of the United States.
Scope and Contents note
Minutes, correspondence, transcripts of forum proceedings, financial records, and printed matter, relating to international organization and the United Nations, and especially to the 22nd World Congress of the World Federalist Movement, held in San Francisco in 1995.
United Nations.; International organization.
- Citizen Organizations Forum on Restructuring the U.N. and Achieving Democratic Global Governance for the 21st Century records, 1994-1995 (Box 1-5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, institutional records, publications, and forum materials.
  - Facilities, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Logo and letterhead, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Portraits and placards, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Cafes and restaurants, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Brochures and programs, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Forum documents (other), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Correspondence to publicize forum (pre-registration), including mailing lists, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Pre-registration miscellaneous correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Lists of forum key persons, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Forum non-participants, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Forum registration payments, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Photos and negatives, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 5 floppy disks, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Forum Transcriptions, 24 June 1995 (Box 1-2)
    - Forum transcriptions - welcome and introductions (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 1 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 2 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 3 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 4 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 5 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 6 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - Forum transcriptions - Morning panels 1, 2, welcome and introductions (Box-folder 2: 1)
      Includes 1 floppy disk
    - Forum transcriptions - panels 3-5 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - Forum transcriptions - panel 6 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Forum transcriptions - correspondence and procedures (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Forum papers, circa 1995 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Panelist Correspondence, 1995
      - Panel 1 Egil Sandberg, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 8)
      - Panel 1 Elizabeth Sveri (chairperson), 1995 (Box-folder 2: 9)
      - Panel 1 Robert von Pagenhardt, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 10)
      - Panel 1 Tom Warrick, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 11)
      - Not attending, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 12)
      - Cherif Bassiouni, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 13)
      - Not attending Michael Closson, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 14)
      - Not attending Lucy Webster, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 15)
      - Panel 1, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 1)
      - Panel 2, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 2)
      - Bente Nielsen-Hansen, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 3)
      - Eugene Carroll, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 4)
      - Charles Overby, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 5)
      - Panel 2 background materials, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 6)
      - Panel 3 (safeguarding democracy) John Anderson, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 7)
      - Panel 3 (safeguarding democracy) Annette Lu, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 8)
      - Panel 3 (safeguarding democracy) Raquel Escobar, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 9)
      - Panel 3 (safeguarding democracy) Jiri Dienstbier, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 10)
      - Panel 3 (safeguarding democracy) Martin Hagvall, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 11)
      - Not attending, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 12)
      - Not attending Kao, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 13)
      - Not attending Latin Americans, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 14)
      - Panel 4 Lucio Levi, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 15)
      - Ali Mazrui, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 16)
      - Panel 4 Background material, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 17)
      - Jan Marie Rushforth, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 18)
      - Lucille Green, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 19)
      - Allan Blakeney, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 20)
      - Menko Rose, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 21)
      - Memo, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 1)
      - Ron Glossop, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - Tad Daley, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 3)
      - Stephen Damours, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 4)
      - Mike Gravel, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - John Logue, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 6)
      - Kenji Utsunomiya, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - Reine Ruge, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Forum coordinators, Robert Muller (keynote), 1995 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Forum coordinators - Laura Upham (introduction), 1995 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Publicity and media - guidelines/examples, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Background Information Articles, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Information on participants, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Interviews, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Miscellaneous forum correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Public relations correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Public relations forum, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Youth '95: Alliance for progressive global change (sponsored by World Federalist Association), 1995 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - U.N. at 50 World Federalists and the Press, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - U.N. 50, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 1-4)
- World Federalist Movement XXII World Congress in San Francisco records, 1994-1996 (Box 5-10)
  - Floppy disks, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    Includes 8 floppy disks
  - Photos, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    Includes 16 slides
  - Council meeting in Glarus, Switzerland, 27 July 1994 - 31 July 1994 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Executive committee meeting, 3 March 1995-5 March 1995 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Post-Copenhangen preparations between World Federalist Association of Northern California and the World Federalist Movement, March 1995- June 1995 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Updates on preparations - circular notices, July 1994-April 1995 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Schedules, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Public relations materials, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Lease for office coordinating Congress and forum, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Insurance for offices at San Francisco State University and Golden Gate University, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Office Equiptment, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Long-distance telephone calls, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Congress staffing - general, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Congress staffing - Yumiko Bird, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Congress staffing - Mursidy Hosin, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Congress staffing - volunteers, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Payroll, 1994 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Printing - Logos by Jeanette Rapp, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Printing - Brochure I, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Printing - Brochure II, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Printing other (letterhead, registration), 1995 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Preparations for ancillary meetings, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - World Federalist Association of Northern California Reception, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Budget and financial correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Congress expenses and accounting, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - World Federalist Association Expenses and accounting - payroll, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Wire transfers and bank statements, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Petty cash reciepts, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Payments, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - World Federalist Association bank statements, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Contributions and correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Budget and finance correspondence, January - July 1995 (Box-folder 7: 4-5)
  - Fundraising, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Contributions, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Grant proposals turned down A-G, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Grant proposals H-Z, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Special Guests, 1995 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Congress speakers, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Registration reports, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Registration correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Registration receipts, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - All registrants, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Registration forms, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Correspondence with San Francisco State University, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 8: 8-9)
  - Congress organization and rooms, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Congress registration and rooms, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - San Francisco Steering committee, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 8: 12-14)
  - Attending from USA, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 15-16)
  - Correspondence with World Federalist Association about activists and youth participants, 1995 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Attending from Canada, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Attending from Czech Republic, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Attending from Denmark, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Attending from France, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Attending from Germany, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Attending from Italy, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Attending from Netherlands, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Attending from Norway, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Attending from Sweden, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Attending from Switzerland, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Attending from the United Kingdom, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Ingo Linsemann, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Russia registration, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Russia correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Nina Bubnova, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - Attending from Ukraine, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - Attending from India, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - Dr. Elton Kessel (funding facilitator), 1995 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - Young Japanese World Federalists, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Toshio Kozai and World Federalists Movement Asian Center, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - Japan - other, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - American Interpreters from English to Japanese, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Algeria: Youcef Aberkane, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Ghana: Agbesi Korku Agbe-Laee, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Ghana - other, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Senegal: Cheikh Ahmadou Bamba Fall, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Africa - other, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Elizeu de Oliveira Chaves, Jr. (Brazilian Youth Committee for the UN, WFM Congress), 1995 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Latin America - other, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Central and South America (Bangladesh, Nepal, Pakistan), 1995 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - East and Southeast Asia (China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Taiwan, Thailand), 1995 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Interpretation - Tom Gardner, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Interpretation - Peter Piro, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - Simultaneous Interpretation correspondence and contacts, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Congress Documents, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Congress - Publicity and media, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Formal packets for delegates, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - Publicity and media, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - Alternative Accommodations, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 18)